League of Legends can be an incredibly
daunting game to get into as a beginner
there are over 160 Champions five
different unique roles items and builds
you have to learn a meta you're supposed
to somehow know immediately and as a new
player it feels like everyone else has
10 years of experience on you well I've
got some good news you're about to learn
the 20 best tips for beginners that will
supercharge your improvement and
speaking of improving fast that's
exactly what we do for you at skill
cap.com we have worldclass courses you
can take right now to learn every role
Top Lane jungle mid lane 80 carry
support we got you covered you then
combine these with our courses on the
essential skills you need macro Wave
Control trading settings and hotkeys
csing Vision mechanics low ELO mistakes
the list goes on then head on over to
our Smurf commentaries select your
Champion to watch live commentaries from
Challenger experts teaching you how to
carry out of the exact rank you're stuck
in you can try all of this out
completely risk-free since if you don't
rank up while Act activ L using skill C
you'll get your money back no questions
asked you can unlock all of this right
now through the discount you can only
get from the link below so what are you
waiting for click the link in the
description below to get the rank you've
always wanted all right so let's start
well at the start of the game the first
thing you need to be aware of as a
beginner are jungler starting locations
wherever a jungler starts they're going
to be pathing to the opposite side of
the map as they clear their camps this
results in them having a very
predictable gang timing at the end at
the same time their camps are going to
be respawning in that same order causing
them to once again path towards that
side of the map resulting in another
gank this creates a concept that's known
as the strong side and weak side if a
jungler starts on the bottom side then
the bottom half of the map is considered
the weak side for that team since he'll
be ganking there less often whereas the
top side is considered the strong side
for their team since they'll be ganking
there more often the trick you want to
implement into your games is to identify
the enemy jungler starting location you
can do this by paying attention to the S
side Lanes at the start of every game
whoever is last to arrive in Lane
usually gave their jungler a leash
letting you predict the jungler's
starting location this then lets you
know if you're the enemy's weak side or
strong side and whether you should be
anticipating ganks the simple counter to
being the enemy strong side is to place
a ward at 2 minutes and 45 seconds this
will catch all the early gang timings by
the enemy jungler the next thing you
need to know is the level two timing
spiking level two while the opponent is
still Level One is by far the most
common and easiest way you're going to
win or lose your lane this is because
being level two gives you more base
stats over the oppon oent while having
access to one additional spell over the
enemy for this reason you need to know
the following level two timings for solo
laners you'll hit level two on the
second minion wave once the first melee
minion dies for bot laners you're going
to hit level two when you've killed
three melee minions or two melees and
one Caster when players first learn
about these timings they always make the
same mistake they wait until they hit
level two and then they try to go
aggressive players are just going to see
you spike level two and back off and
play safe so the skill you want to
develop is positioning yourself so
you're within engage range before you
hit Level two so you can instantly
punish the enemy once you get better you
can even time your engage slightly
before you hit Level Two so then you
level up during the fight so now you're
wondering should you be fighting for
level two every single time then well
yes but only if you're in a ranged vers
ranged or melee vers melee matchup
ranged vers melee matchups are unique
and something you must learn a super
common beginner mistake is to try and
fight for the push as the melee Champion
you're going to get destroyed if you do
this the fact that the range Champion
has access to a ranged Auto attack at
level one while you only have access to
one spell means trying to hit level two
more often than not results in you
losing all of your health instead the
default game plan if you're the melee
Champion is to sit back conserve your
health even giving up last hits if
needed you then wait until the minions
crash into your Tower and then once you
hit Level three you'll have all your
basic abilities and a full health pool
that's your time to start going
aggressive which works more often than
not due to the enemy range Champion
being super pushed up the lane now
you're probably wondering well what is
the range Champion supposed to do then
well this is the next thing you need to
know rebounds a rebound happens when you
push a wave into a tower 99% of the time
it's going to cause the minions to then
push back towards you this is where the
name comes from it's like you're
rebounding the minions off the tower the
reason this happens is that the next
incoming wave will start damaging the
wave much sooner since it's closer to
that side of the map the only time it
doesn't rebound is when the wave gets
cleared before the next wave gets stuck
on it this is called a reset as the wave
now goes back to neutral at the center
of the lane so in a Range first melee
matchup when the range Champion crashes
the wave they can know a rebound is
going to happen this means it's now
their turn to play safe giving up
minions as needed as it bounces back to
them to a safer position or if they got
the melee Champion low they can use it
to set up a Kill by forcing them to
overextend for last hits rebounds go way
beyond that though as they're basically
what will let you leave Lane need to
recall well push the wave which sets up
a rebound now you can recall and as you
head back to Lane the wave is bouncing
back to you so you miss practically no
minions want to roam again push the wave
first go off and Roam and then head back
to Lane with the wave pushing back to
you missing very few minions now you
might be thinking so does that mean each
person is just taking turns rebounding
waves to one another well honestly yeah
a lot of lanes do end up feeling turnbas
like that but there is one exception
freezing freezing is one of the most
misunderstood things in League at its
core it is simple you just make sure the
enemy has around four to five more
minions than your wave and you can just
permanently keep the wave Frozen in
front of your Tower what new players get
wrong when they first learn this is they
try to freeze as a way to keep
themselves safe this is impossible if
you're losing the enem is just going to
be able to walk up push the wave and you
can't fight them and instead freezing is
done only when you're the one with the
lead this is because it forces the enemy
to have to overextend to last hit
minions at which point you can fight
them with your lead often killing them
or if they don't extend they just bleed
out a ton of farm over time to the
freeze and speaking of fighting a
beginner mistake players make is
fighting way too much the concept you
need to know to fix this is called Dead
time dead time is the period of time
when either all your jungle camps are
dead or the minions in Lane are dead and
you're waiting for the next wave to
arrive this is the most efficient time
for you to fight since you're not giving
up any gold or experience from those
minions or Monsters I know that it feels
like if you don't react to a fight
you're going to fall behind from the
enemy getting kills but this is a
misconception in the early game simply
farming one wave and one turret plate is
nearly worth the same as a kill in the
mid to late game if someone leaves an
inner turret undefended that's 700 gold
from the tower and just two waves on top
of that equals 300 gold so suddenly
simply pushing two waves and taking a
tower is more than getting three kills
worth of gold as a beginner you really
shouldn't be fighting outside of your
dead time you learn as you get better
the exceptions to the rule the other
mistake you want to avoid is staying on
the map for too long when you have
unspent gold it's really easy to make
this mistake since you'll be on the map
getting a ton of kills and feel like
you're stronger than the enemy but
unless you spend that gold you're
actually weaker since by killing them
they got to go back to base and spend
their gold and get a stat Advantage by
purchasing items a really good rule of
thumb to follow is to start planning
your recall once you pass 1,000 gold a
lot of items are around that amount like
faded ashes and serrated Dirk for
example that being said as you get more
experience you want to identify your
next item SP and recall once you pass
that amount so for a lot of Mages mid
that would be lost chapter at 1,200 gold
for example or hextech alternator at
1100 or for a lot of bruisers that can
be Tiamat at 12200 and another mistake
to look out for when it comes to
recalling is getting baited by turret
plates early on a lot of the time when
newer players find out turret plates
give 125 gold each well they end up
throwing their whole Lane trying to get
one this happens most often after you
get a kill on your lane opponent you'll
figure hey they're dead and despite
sitting on a lot of gold and being low
on resources like health and Mana you'll
mistakenly think you have enough time to
take that turret plate and then recall
after but death timers are very short
early on and when you die you get home
guards which gets you back to Lane
really fast so by staying for that plate
you'll end up low on resources stuck in
lane or having to recall on a bad timing
now our final tip in the laning phase is
that speed really matters in league for
example here Talia is going to be simply
better and thus faster at clearing her
jungle than the enemy Master ye the
result of this is Talia is able to fully
clear all six camps in her jungle in the
same time Master ye could only clear
five this means when they both arrive
top Talia is an entire level up from
that extra camp this not only denies
Master ye a gank on top but also gets
him low while then giving Talia the
Scuttle which ends up turning into an
easy kill all of this was made possible
simply due to the fact that Talia spent
time optimizing her clear and so was
just faster side note this is why we
created a course teaching the fastest
way to clear on each Champion it's
extremely effective for climbing ranks
there are many ways you can save time in
leagues though it's not just jungle
clears for example if your Champion can
One-Shot the Caster minions with an
ability it can often be better to move
as far up the lane as you can to then
cast the ability on the melee minions
then once the wave meets you can hit the
entire wave clearing it all at once this
will then give you extra time between
waves you can use to roam recoil or
pressure Towers faster in fact one of
the best ways to be faster isn't
mechanical but actually with
decision-making for example here Talia
is reacting to a possible fight but by
recognizing and accepting the fight is
lost early on it means she's pivoting to
her next source of gold way faster than
if she was tunneling on the fight and
trying to get a kill thus generating
more gold per second for her honestly if
you just go for guaranteed gold while
focusing on being faster at doing it
you're going to be miles ahead of your
opponents now let's get into mechanics
there are five mechanics as a beginner
you must know first is that in League
clicking closer to your Champion gives
you a big Edge over your opponent this
is because when a skill shot is thrown
at you your mouse has to move less
distance to then send a movement command
in a different Direction Compare this to
when you're clicking far away and you
can see how much more distance your
mouse has to cover and how hard it is to
dodge abilities of course if you have to
Auto attack or cast a spell further away
that's fine but for movement commands
you typically want to keep them close to
your Champion the next mechanic you need
to be using is sending movement commands
between Auto attacks your auto attack
has two parts to its animation the wind
up and the wind down the animation up
until the projectile releases is the
wind up or for melee Champions up until
you do damage to the enemy it's really
bad to send a movement command during
this time since it's going to cancel
your auto attack and do no damage the
animation that plays after the
projectile releases or the damage is
applied as a melee Champion is the wind
down animation this can be canceled with
a movement command and by moving between
our Auto attacks we make ourselves very
hard to hit and can cover a lot more
distance if we're either chasing or
kiing in addition to this you absolutely
must use What's called the attack move
command this is essential since if you
don't use it if you misclick the ground
beside an enemy you're going to be
walking into them attack moving makes
your Champion attack the nearest enemy
even if you misclick on the ground
beside them there are a few settings
though you need to use for this to work
properly first enable attack move on
cursor this makes you attack the nearest
Target to your cursor instead of your
champion this is way better since if you
don't have this enabled and try to
attack an enemy behind someone well
you're just going to be hitting the
closest Target to your Champion instead
next is show attack range this will show
you a circle around your champion of
your attack range every time you press
the default attack move bind of a on
your keyboard this is really helpful
since it lets you know how you should be
positioning now you can use other attack
move binds but that's outside the scope
of this guide we've created more
in-depth guides on that for now just
enable those settings and use the A
hotkey and then left click to send
attack move commands if you're new to
this mechanic the next setting you need
to be aware of is quick casting this
gives you such a huge Advantage as it
makes you cast your spells way faster
since as soon as you press your spell
key it's going to immediately fire now I
know what you're thinking well then I
can't actually aim my ability here's the
trick that players use they bind their
normal cast to shift plus that ability
so shift plus Q shift plus W shift plus
e shift plus r this way if you need to
combo fast you can just press your
abilities as normal but if you need to
line up a skill shot you can press shift
and the ability to aim it you'll also
need this backup shift bind for warding
this is because you need the aim
indicator to know when it's being placed
in a brush since it will turn green and
at the same time the circle is going to
let you know how far the ward sees so
you know you're actually covering choke
points and and the final mechanic you
need is to unlock your camera for a lot
of players this can feel awkward but it
gives you a big advantage since you can
pan your camera to see way more
information when you're fighting while
at the same time it lets you see more
angles you can expect enemies to come
from so you can react sooner there are
some really simple exercises to get
yourself used to this mechanic head into
practice Mode start by nudging your
camera so that your Champion always
stays on the edge of your screen after
this practice moving in straight lines
where you click around the center of
your screen and Edge your camera to keep
your Champion close to the edge once you
master this head into the river again
you're right clicking around the halfway
point of your screen then Ned your
camera up spam right click then left
spam right click and repeat you then
want to go back down the river the other
way nudge your camera down spam right
click then right spam right click and
repeat by the way if you're interested
in learning more about mechanics and
settings and hotkeys then I highly
recommend these two Great Courses on our
website great now let's talk about what
you need to know in the mid to like game
the mid game starts around 14 minutes
when turret plates fall that's when
players can start moving around the map
more and the L game is usually around 25
to 30 minutes when things like dragon
soul become a threat for a team to take
so firstly during this time in the game
you should be aware of a concept called
gold inflation in League having early
gold leads are much more impactful
because they represent a larger
percentage of the total gold in the game
for example if someone has 6K gold and
you have 3K gold for a 3K gold lead on
you at 10 minutes well that means
they're 100% more powerful than you are
in terms of items but if that same
person has a 3K gold Advantage at 25
minutes when you have 13k gold and they
have 16k gold well that's only around
16% more powerful than you and it goes
without saying when everyone is full
build then gold leads don't even matter
at that point since you can't convert
that extra gold into items long story
short when you're behind early on just
by delaying the game even if you don't
shorten the gold lead or even if it gets
worse it's actually still an improvement
due to how gold inflation works now the
next thing you're about to learn is the
foundational concept to all other macro
Concepts in League number advantages the
vast majority of all fights you will
have in League of Legends won't be
decided by gold leads mechanics or the
champ ion types it's going to be decided
by which team has more players at that
fight and most players really struggle
with map awareness and so they're
constantly taking fights where they're
outnumbered Without Really realizing it
the solution to this is simple once
turret plates fall at 14 minutes and the
mid game hits you need to be looking at
the map a lot the goal is to identify
what teammates you have nearby and what
enemies you can see on the map if you
can only see two enemies and three other
are missing well play it safe if your
team is grouped do five and you see one
enemy in the sidelane awesome look to
fight you know you have the number
Advantage literally every macro tactic
you're going to learn when you're more
experienced just Builds on this one
principle so it's best to focus on
getting good at this first the next
thing to be aware of during the mid to
late game is the pressure rule the basic
concept of pressure is defined as when
someone on your team is threatening to
damage a tower this is because to do
this they're also pushing a wave into
the tower so they're threatening two
things one to just straight up destroy
the tower which can be worth a lot of
gold and two for the wave they push to
then die to the tower this is a loss of
golden experience for the enemy team if
no one comes to pick up that wave in the
mid to late game simply look at the the
map and identify if your team has
pressure when they do then you need to
be pressuring too in some way that can
mean grouping with them to pressure the
same Tower it can mean pressuring a
completely separate Tower or it can mean
looking to take a neutral objective you
do this for two reasons firstly it's
incredibly hard to defend when an entire
team coordinates pressure at the same
time it just works the majority of the
time in Solo Q secondly when your team
is pressuring they're often going to get
some sort of Defense from the enemy team
so if you don't match their pressure and
you go off to farm safely well you're
likely leaving your team down in numbers
for that upcoming fight the inverse of
this is also true so when your team has
no pressure well that's your time to
focus on playing defensive safe and look
to passively farm rather than pressure
yourself the next mid to late game rule
to follow is the empty Lane rule before
you do anything you want to pay
attention to if there's empty lanes and
push them out before you really do much
remember what you just learned about
pressure by pushing waves you create
pressure this will set up two simple but
effective tactics either no one from the
enemy team defends that push which means
tons of free gold and experience for you
or by pushing you bait a Defender from
the enemy team to respond to it at which
point you can rotate off while the enemy
is busy with the wave to look for a
number Advantage fight elsewhere if you
just follow the following three things
number advantages the pressure rule and
the empty Lane rule you're going to be
ahead of like 90% of the player base as
a new player also I quickly want to
mention a common trap newer players fall
for in the mid delay game they try to
take Inhibitors before taking Baron
League of Legends isn't designed for
this to happen it will be really easy
for one or two Champions on the enemy
team just to clear that wave in an
instant and defend the tower you'll
waste a lot of time getting not a lot
done while being very overextended at
the enemy's base it's the most common
way leads are thrown instead league is
designed for you to take Baron first and
then use that Baron buff to Siege Towers
to then take the Inhibitors you want to
set up your Baron takes with two simple
Steps step one push out mid lane
remember it creates pressure and pins
down enemies defending it this will give
you a timing window to go and get vision
control around Baron this means using
sweepers and control Wards to clear the
enemy's Vision around Baron and then
placing your own Vision deeper into the
enemy's jungle so you can see them early
on if they come to try and contest your
Baron take step two is then starting the
baron if you pushed Mid First and
established vision control the vast
majority of the time you're going to get
Baron for free uncontested however if
you see the enemy is moving to contest
your Baron take then you want to stop
doing Baron and instead move to make a
pick on them since you clear their
Vision first they won't know you're
there making for easy kills those easy
kills mean you have the number Advantage
so you can just go back to taking Baron
after and finally our last beginner tip
has to do with setting realistic
expectations there's a reason why
players refer to grinding solo quue as
well a grind let's say you were bronze 4
if you maintained a 55% win rate it
would take you0 games on average to get
to Silver 4 bronze has an average game
duration of 30 minutes that means this
will take you 80 hours of playing and if
you played 3 hours a day every day it
would still take you 27 days to get to
Silver at the same time a very
reasonable expectation you should
develop is that around one out of three
of the games you play will be unwinable
you don't know which games those will be
so you still have to be levelheaded and
try your best best no matter how doomed
the games feel and I know that losing
one in three games sounds like a lot
that would still mean you'd have a 66%
win rate which is incredibly high and
makes for a fast climb that's why it's
really important to have a healthy
long-term mentality when playing this
game and try not to let the short-term
losses mean too much to you and if you
want to make that grind way easier then
you need skillcap tocom we have
worldclass courses you can take right
now to learn every role Top Lane jungle
mid lane 80 carry support we got you
covered you then combine these with our
courses on the essential skills you need
macro Wave Control trading settings and
hotkeys csing Vision mechanics low ELO
mistakes the list goes on then head on
over to our Smurf commentaries select
your Champion to watch live commentaries
from Challenger experts teaching you how
to carry out of the exact rank you're
stuck in you can try all of this out
completely risk-free since if you don't
rank up while actively using skill cap
you'll get your money back no questions
asked you can unlock all of this right
now through the discount you can only
get from the link below so what are you
waiting for click the link in the
description below to get the rank you've
always wanted all right and that will do
it for this one we here at skillcap want
to thank you for watching and we'll
catch you in the next one